Guide to the Washington State University Agricultural Engineering Department Records 1932-1974
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington State University Agricultural Engineering Department Records
1932-1974
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 111
Washington State University. Agricultural Engineering Department.
12 Linear feet of shelf space 12 Boxes 12600 Items (approximate)
The collection consists mainly of memoranda, correspondence, minutes, and reports of the Washington State University Agricultural Engineering Department. The bulk of the material dates from 1947-1973, during June Roberts' departmental chairmanship.
The Department of Agricultural Engineering was first organized in 1909. In 1926 a four year professional course began, the work being jointly administered by the Deans of the College of Agriculture and the College of Engineering. The divided administration remains in 1983. The College of Engineering administers the curriculum; the College of Agriculture administers the research and the Cooperative Extension work. Students enrolled in the department are from both colleges. Some graduate from the College of Engineering with a degree in Agricultural Engineering. Others graduate from the College of Agriculture with a Farm Mechanization specialty.
The collection consists mainly of memoranda, correspondence, minutes, and reports of the Washington State University Agricultural Engineering Department, arranged into 4 series. The bulk of the material dates from 1947-1973, during June Roberts' departmental chairmanship.
Series 1. Alphabetical Subject File, 1937-1974, consists of general departmental office files, 1937-1979, and is divided into two subseries. Washington State University covers activities at Washington State University and affiliated work in the state of Washington, 1937-1974. The bulk of the material dates from 1947-1973, during June Roberts' departmental chairmanship, and consists mainly of memoranda, correspondence, minutes, and reports. West Pakistan University File 1954-1971, consist almost exclusively of correspondence among Pullman-based office personnel, staff members in Pakistan, and potential employees.
Series 2. Professional Organizations, 1947-1974, deals with three organizations in which June Roberts was an active member. The materials especially stress activities of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers, where Mr. Roberts held many national offices.
Series 3. Photographs, 1934-1974. The prints and negatives are mainly of research projects. Many photographs within the machinery files are items provided by manufacturing companies.
Series 4. Financial Ledgers, 1932-1973. These ledgers contain a noncontiguous record of the accounts of the department, concentrating on research activities. The series also contains the ledgers of accounts for the Washington Council on the Relationship of Electricity to Agriculture, a major source of funding for the department's early research and extension work. The records indicate that the name was changed to the present Washington Farm Electrification Committee around 1947.
The collection is arranged into 4 series:
Series 1. Alphabetical Subject File, 1937-1974, is divided into two subseries.
1.1 Washington State University. The folders are arranged in a single alphabetical subseries, in which the processor has attempted to retain the original order where possible. Loose material not fitting into the established filing system is placed in a folder labeled "Unfiled Material." Because of dual nature of the administration of Agricultural Engineering there is some duplication of subject files. These files are further labeled with the relevant college names.
1.2 West Pakistan University File, 1954-1971. The files are arranged in a single alphabetical subject series. The original folder names and the order of materials within folders is retained.
Series 2. Professional Organizations, 1947-1974, is arranged alphabetically by organization, then by date or subject.
Series 3. Photographs, 1934-1974. The project files are arranged numerically by project number, while subject files arranged alphabetically by subject. The original file names have been retained, reflecting a system of labeling and dating each print and negative, which was used during the 1950s. Photos dated before and after that decade are largely undated and many are unlabeled. Prints and negatives with no labels have been placed in a general file.
Series 4. Financial Ledgers, 1932-1973. The original folder names and the order of materials within folders is retained.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The records of the Agricultural Engineering Department (UA 80-1) were transferred to the University Archives of Washington State University in March 1980 by the department in accordance with established records schedules.
For further information on Washington State University's Pakistan Project see the Pakistan Project (WSU-AID Contract) Records, 1952-1972 (Archives 26)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Agricultural Engineering Department -- Records and correspondence.; State College of Washington. Agricultural Engineering Department -- Records and correspondence.; State College of Washington. Agricultural Engineering Department.
Agricultural engineering.
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State); Agriculture
- Series 1. Alphabetical Subject File, 1937-1974
  - 1.1. Washington State University
    - Admissions, 1968-1971; 15 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Affirmative Action, 1972-1973; 27 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Agricultural Economics, 1970; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Agricultural Engineering
      - Departmental Report, 1937; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Staff and Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1954-1973; 700 items (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Agronomy Farm
      - 1955-1957, 30 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Water Rights, 1955-1958; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Animal Sciences, 1969-1973; 15 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report-College of Engineering, 1971-1973; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "A" Miscellaneous, 1955-1973; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Banquet
      - AGAWARDS and Scholarships, 1970-1972; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Students-Alumni, 1969-1970; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Student-Faculty-Alumni, 1969-1970; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Beasley, Wallace Memos and Correspondence
      - 1966-1970, 30 items (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - 1971-1973, 15 items (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bertramson, B. R. Memos and Correspondence, 1969-1973; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "B" Miscellaneous, 1966-1971; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Capital Improvement, 1958-1970; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Capital Outlay, 1949-1962; 100 items (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Careers Through Curriculum at Washington State University, 1969; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Catalog Committee, 1969-1970; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Census of Enrollment, 1963-1973; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - College of Agriculture
      - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1953-1964; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Office of the Dean, 1952-1972; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956-1973; 200 items (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - College of Engineering
      - Advisory Board, 1969-1973; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Department Chairmen Meetings, 1959-1969; 70 items (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Office of the Dean, 1968-1973; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Miscellaneous, 1962-1973; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Committee on Instruction, 1954-1972; 200 items (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Community College Transfer, 1970-1972; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Comprehensive Review, 1960; 70 items (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Compton Union Building, 1966-1971; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Computer Center, 1969-1973; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Controller-Correspondence and Memos
      - 1958-1964, 10 items (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - 1964-1973, 50 items (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Cooperative State Research Service Review, 1972-1972; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence-Miscellaneous
      - A-E, 1969-1973; 25 items (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - F-K, 1971-1973; 50 items (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - L-W, 1971-1973; 25 items (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Course Expansion, 1969; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Course Outlines, 1968-1970; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Current Research information Service, 1968-1970; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Curricula and Catalog Changes
      - 1959, 25 items (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - 1960-1969, 250 items (Box 2, Folder 47-48)
      - 1970-1973, 100 items (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Curriculum
      - Advisory Program, 1954-1972; 25 items (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - At Other Schools, 1964-1971; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Committee-College of Agriculture, 1954-1963; 50 items (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Evaluation, 1961-1962; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Review, 1959-1965; 50 items (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Miscellaneous, 1964-1972; 50 items (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Duplicating and Mailing, 1963-1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "E" Miscellaneous, 1967-1971; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Educational Policies Committee, 1964-1971; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Engineers- Council For Professional Development Review
      - Notes, 1949-1950; 25 items (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Notes, 1960-1965; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Notes, 1966-1972; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - Report, 1960; 75 items (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - Report, 1966; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Report, 1971; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Engineering Coordinating Council, 1953-1956; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Enrollment Statistics
      - College of Agriculture, 1957-1972; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - College of Engineering, 1964-1971; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Enviromental
      - Engineering, 1971-1972; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Protection Agency, 1973; 3 items (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - Science Program, 1969-1970; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Equipment, 1970-1973; 8 items (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Evaluation Reports Miscellaneous, 1964; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Extension
      - Cosgriffe, Harry A. - Correspondence and Memos, 1969-1972; 80 items (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Engineering, 1961-1970; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Hagood, Mel A. - Correspondence and Reports, 1966-1973; 80 items (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Middleton, J. E. Correspondence and Reports, 1966-1973; 80 items (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Personnel and Program Review, 1966; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Western Region Plan Exchange Committee, 1965-1971; 50 items (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959-1978; 50 items (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - "F" Miscellaneous, 1955-1973; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Facilities
      - Advisory Committee, 1973; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 82)
      - Planning, 1969-1972; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Faculty
      - Activity Reports, 1972-1973; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 84)
      - Assignment, 1965-1973; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 85)
      - Service Report, 1966-1968; 40 items (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Financial Aid, 1967-1971; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Food Service
      - 1965-1969, 20 items (Box 3, Folder 88)
      - 1970-1972, 30 items (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Forestry, 1965-1970; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Full Time Equivalent, 1964-1971; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - General Services, 1966-1971; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Gifts and Grants, Grants-in-Aid Policy, 1952-1960; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Goals of Engineering Education Study, College of Engineering, 1964-1966; 4 items (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Graduate
      - Faculty, 1952-1971; 75 items (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - Students, 1970-1971; 16 items (Box 3, Folder 96)
      - Studies in Engineering Sciences, 1963-1971; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Graduates in Agricultural Engineering and Agricultural Mechanization, 1956-1972; 30 items (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Ground Water Use, 1960-1968; 30 items (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Hartzog, David, 1948-1958; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Honors Program, 1964-1972; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Horticulture - Agricultural Engineering Joint Projects, 1966-1973; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Institute of Agricultural Sciences
      - Building Study, 1956; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - Capital Outlay, 1952-1956; 40 items (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Institute of Technology Advisory Board
      - 1956-1957, 7 items (Box 3, Folder 105)
      - 1958-1960, 10 items (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Institutional Studies, 1970-1972; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Instructional Cost - Equipment, 1972; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - International Harvester - Loaned Equipment, 1956-1972; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Introduction to Ag Course, 1964-1966; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - "I" Miscellaneous, 1965-1970; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Kimbrell, Jack T. - Correspondence and Memos, 1969-1971; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Land-Grant Colleges Funding, 1970; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Lease Agreement, 1963-1971; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Leave Guidelines, 1970-1974; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Libraries, 1963-1970; 30 items (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Long Range Planning
      - 1955-1967, 40 items (Box 3, Folder 117)
      - 1966-1967, 250 items (Box 3, Folder 118-119)
    - Madsen, Louis L.- Memos and Correspondence, 1963-1972; 150 items (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Maintenance Agreement
      - Honeywell, 1969-1971; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 121)
      - Terminal Services, 1972; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Model Community, 1970-1975; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - News Bureau, 1969-1970; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Nielson, James.- Memos, 1971-1973; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Northwest Washington Experiment Station, 1971-1973; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Office of Staff Personnel, 1972; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Oregon State University, 1971-1972; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Personnel, 1967-1970; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Personnel Roster - College of Engineering, 1971-1976; 3 items (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Pettibone, Carl A., 1978; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - PhD Program, 1967-1971; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Physics Department, 1970-1972; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Physical Plant Correspondence, 1964-1974; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Placement, 1971-1975; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Potato Research, 1956-1977; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Professional Exams, 1953-1971; 60 items (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Property Inventory Changes, 1954-1973; 50 items (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Proposed Publications, 1963-1964; 15 items (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Purchasing, 1955-1972; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Puyallup Capital Improvement, 1952-1957; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Rasmussen, Lowell W. - Memos, 1971-1972; 15 items (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Receipts and Purchasing, 1955; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Recruiting Policy, 1970-1973; 40 items (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Registrars Office, 1968-1972; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Relocation Expenses, 1973; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Remodeling and Expansion of Buildings, 1947-1970; 200 items (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Research
      - Account Transfers, 1969-1973; 15 items (Box 4, Folder 148)
      - Assistants, 1971-1972; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 149)
      - Cooperative State Research Service, 1964-1972; 50 items (Box 4, Folder 150)
      - Editor, 1968-1972; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 151)
      - Progress Report, 1964-1972; 100 items (Box 4, Folder 152)
      - Project 0241, 1974; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - Project 1720, 1963-1972; 150 items (Box 4, Folder 154)
      - Project Listings, 1956-1974; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 155)
      - Proposal 6/7700 - 6057, 1966-1968; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 156)
      - Proposal for Pakistan, 1969-1970; 40 items (Box 4, Folder 157)
      - Proposals Miscellaneous, 1968-1974; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 158)
      - Regional Projects, 1970-1973; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 159)
      - Miscellaneous, 1969-1973; 200 items (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Rural Development, 1970; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Safety and Security, 1970-1972; 40 items (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Salary, 1972-1973; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Scholarships, 1973-1974; 50 items (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Science Library, 1969-1973; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Security Guidelines, 1970; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Shelton, V. L. - Memos and Correspondence, 1962-1972; 50 items (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Short Course
      - Irrigation Problems
        - 1953, 30 items (Box 5, Folder 168)
        - 1955-1959, 100 items (Box 5, Folder 169)
        - 1960-1965, 100 items (Box 5, Folder 170)
        - 1966-1967, 80 items (Box 5, Folder 171)
        - 1968-1969, 150 items (Box 5, Folder 172)
        - 1970-1972, 150 items (Box 5, Folder 173)
      - Materials Handling, 1963; 30 items (Folder 174)
      - Skills Conversation in Food Engineering, 1972; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 175)
      - Miscellaneous, 1951-1972; 200 items (Box 5, Folder 176-177)
    - Small Class Requests, 1952-1970; 80 items (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Smith, Alan H. - Memos, 1970-1971; 20 items (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Space Inventory, 1969-1973; 20 items (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Space Utilization Survey - College of Agriculture, 1970-1973; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Spiegman, John P. - Memos and Correspondence, 1963-1969; 30 items (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Strait, Leland C. Memos and Correspondence, 1964-1971; 50 items (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Student Evaluation of Instruction, 1967-1971; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Summer Session, 1955-1972; 50 items (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - "S" Miscellaneous, 1969-1974; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Temporary Course Approval, 1953-1966; 50 items (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Time Schedule Material, 1959-1971; 75 items (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Travel Authorization, 1959-1971; 100 items (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Travel Policy, 1973; 5 items (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Transfer of Funds
      - 1963-1968, 30 items (Box 5, Folder 192)
      - 1969-1971, 30 items (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Unfiled Material, 1956-1972; 40 items (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - University of Idaho Cooperative Courses, 1962-1972; 20 items (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - University Senate, 1975-1977; 5 items (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - "U" Miscellaneous, 1969; 2 items (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Vehicles, 1947-1967; 20 items (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Washington Water Resources Center, 1964-1971; 40 items (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Washington Wheat Commission, 1958-1971; 15 items (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Water Resources Coordinating Act, 1962-1963; 5 items (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Western Washington Experiment Station, 1952-1971; 150 items (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - 1.2. West Pakistan University File, 1954-1971
    - Agricultural Engineering Catalog, 1963; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Agricultural Engineering Positions - AID Contract, 1967; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Bach, W. Kenneth, 1964-1965; 20 items (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Brown, Owen K., 1963; 20 items (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - Buchanan, M.T., 1960-1962; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - Busch, Charles D., 1964-1967; 5 items (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1954-1971; 30 items (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Contracts, Agreements, etc., 1961-1964; 5 items (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Curriculum, Books, Etc., 1961-1969; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Description of West Pakistan University, 1961; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Equipment, Plans, Etc., 1963; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - Friberg, Walt, 1961-1968; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 214-215)
    - Job Description
      - Agricultural Engineer, 1964; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 216)
      - Irrigation Engineer, 1963-1966; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Letters
      - To Other institutions For Prospective Applicants, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 218)
      - To Prospective Applicants, 1964-1968; 30 items (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Living in Lyallpur, 1961; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - Pakistan Participants on WSU Campus, 1962-1964; 5 items (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Pakistan Pictures, 1967-1968; 11 items (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Proposed Feed Plant, 1956-1961; 300 items (Box 6, Folder 223-224)
    - Prospective Employees, 1962; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 225)
    - Replies
      - Applicants - Active, 1964-1966; 20 items (Box 6, Folder 226)
      - Applicants - "Dead", 1961-1964; 100 items (Box 6, Folder 227)
      - From Others Re: Prospective Applicants, 1964; 3 items (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Shaw, C.G., 1969; 4 items (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Students, Miscellaneous, 1964-1968; 6 items (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Swenson, S.P.- Campus Coordinator
      - Memos and Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 231)
      - Memos and Correspondence, 1964-1969; 40 items (Box 6, Folder 232)
      - Reports, 1964-1969; 9 items (Box 6, Folder 233)
    - Wahla, Mohammed Iqbal, 1965; 4 items (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - WSU - Pakistan Cooperative Agreement, 1967; 6 items (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Well and Pump, 1960-1963; 7 items (Box 6, Folder 236)
- Series 2. Professional Organizations, 1947-1974
  - 2.1. American Society of Agricultural Engineers
    - Annual Meeting in Pullman, 1971; 31 items (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - Building Fund Campaign, 1968; 25 items (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - Curriculum and Course Content Committee, 1957-1964; 40 items (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - Correspondence
      - With Assistant Secretary, 1952-1957; 30 items (Box 7, Folder 240)
      - With Executive Secretary, 1959-1965; 30 items (Box 7, Folder 241)
    - Council on Fertilizer Application, 1955-1966; 20 items (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - Electric Infrared Brooding Committee, 1954-1956; 255 items (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - Electric Utilization Research Conference Committee, 1960-1973; 50 items (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Executive Committee of the Education and Research Division, 1956-1971; 50 items (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Films, 1960-1963; 3 items (Box 7, Folder 246)
    - Pacific Northwest Region, 1960-1970; 12 items (Box 7, Folder 247)
    - Pullman Meeting of the Pacific Northwest Section, 1957; 50 items (Box 7, Folder 248)
    - State Section Proposal, 1957-1958; 25 items (Box 7, Folder 249)
    - Student Enrollment and Recruitment, 1957-1964; 20 items (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - 2.2. General
    - 1947-1949, 50 items (Box 7, Folder 251)
    - 1950-1959, 550 items (Box 7, Folder 252-255)
    - 1960-1969, 350 items (Box 8, Folder 256-258)
    - 1970-1973, 100 items (Box 8, Folder 259)
  - 2.3. American Society for Engineering Education
    - 1945-1956, 100 items (Box 8, Folder 260)
    - 1957-1960, 100 items (Box 8, Folder 261)
  - 2.4. Western Soil and Water Research Committee
    - 1967-1968, 14 items (Box 8, Folder 262)
    - 1969, 32 items (Box 8, Folder 263)
    - 1970-1971, 23 items (Box 8, Folder 264)
    - 1972-1973, 36 items (Box 8, Folder 265)
    - 1974, 58 items (Box 8, Folder 266)
- Series 3. Photographs, 1934-1974.
  - Projects
    - 789-Machinery, Experimental, undated; 59 items (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - 802-Heat Lamp Brooding, 1953; 14 items (Box 9, Folder 268)
    - 878-Silo Preservation, 1953-1956; 70 items (Box 9, Folder 269)
    - 946-Use of Aluminum, 1953; 1 item (Box 9, Folder 270)
    - 964, undated; 48 items (Box 9, Folder 271)